## **Kevin Andres**

| $\mathcal{C}$ | 176 | 1160 | 8662  |                        | ch.eu  | Beijing       |
|---------------|-----|------|-------|------------------------|--------|---------------|
| 3             | kev | Dr3  | in li | nkedin.com/in/k-andres | 🖵 gitl | hub.com/Draym |



## Software Engineer

Software engineer with 4+ years of enterprise experience in full-stack development, mainly using Java/NodeJs and ReactJs while participating in the complete product development lifecycle within Agile teams. Specializing in backend development and micro-services architecture on cloud services.

Animated by well-designed code and discovering new business problematics; motivated by novelty and tackle technical & design challenges. Passionate in User problematics, AI Robotics, Finance, Energy, Data and more.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Software Engineer Backend

Jul 2020 - Present

Stey - startup in the lodging industry

Beijing - China

Responsible for the backend development within micro-services architectures of +20 services written in Kotlin and Scala. Use of Azure cloud, Azure CI, Kubernetes, SpringCloud and event streams with Kafka.

- · Creation and configuration of new API modules as micro-services
- Housekeep operations task management system(tenant, hotel, rent) designed under Akka message-driven principals and Kafka event streams.
- Tencent SMS & Chat API integration
- IOT third-parties APIs integration for connected rooms
- new Digital invoices and contracts management
  - WeChat & Alipay APIs for mobile payment; transactions tracking and reporting
  - legal E-signing, automatic billing, IOT locker, PDF generation
  - kotlin first PDF generation library based on generic grid design including a markdown interpreter
- Migrate Hibernate JPA to Exposed, refactor services to SOLID principles

## Full-Stack Developer

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

Scottish Power - energy company

Glasgow - Scotland

- Migration ASP.Net websites to React web-apps following PWA norms. Achieving 100 scores on Lighthouse, integrating push-notifications, cache, offline mode, and optimizations on ReactJs. Creation of an intern CMS.
- Webapp in React & Redux to display electricity data and shortcuts all over the UK
- Responsible for designing and developing a complete Push-Notification administration ecosystem
  - RestAPI (Spring) managing push notifications and events triggered by third party services
  - Webapp (React) with Kerberos login to administrate notification streams and manage data reports
  - Successfully designed prototypes and deployed to production on JBoss with APIs behind WSO2
- Supervision and mentor of an intern for the development of chatbots on NodeJs with IBM Watson

# Software Developer

Jan 2018 - Nov 2018

Linnworks - leading E-commerce management software in the UK

Portsmouth - England

Features to handle e-commerce warehouse management tools. Promoting customer-centric approach.

- · web-apps using .Net, Angular and bootstrap for mini-apps development
- C# pluggins using API SDKs & complex SQL scripts as automated macro
- third-party APIs integration for Global-E and Magento 2.0

### **EDUCATION**

### Epitech - European Institute of Information Technology

Jul 2012 - Dec 2017

Master Information Technology

Paris

**Beijing Jiaotong University** 

Sep 2016 - Jun 2017

Master Software Engineering

Beijing

### **SKILLS LIST**

French native; English professional; Chinese beginner

- Language: Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, Scala, C++, Go
- Back-End: Spring Boot/Cloud/Security & Kerberos, Lagom, Akka, Kafka, Play, Express.js, Maven, RestAPI, micro-services, Redis, Zipkin, Swagger, JUnit, Mockito
- Front-End: ReactJs, AngularJS & Angular, Html & CSS, Bootstrap
- DB & Tools: SQL, MongoDB, Elastic Search, Exposed, Hibernate & JPA, Slick, Mybatis, Jooq
- Tools: Kubernetes, Azure, Agile processes, Git, NodeJs, Nginx, JBoss, AWS, Jira, Docker, Windows/Linux